I see. You've been in Seiran.
그동안 세이란에 계셨군요
Yes. I learned that Togetsu had sent their men to Suoh.
맞아, 토게츠에서 스오에 사람을 보냈다기에
So I fended them off.
얼른 물리쳐버렸어
Did you fend them off all by yourself?
후부키 연대장님 혼자서요?
That's impossible. I had some help from the Seiran soldiers.
그럴리가, 세이란군의 도움을 받았어
By the way, can you brief me about
그나저나 지금까지의 일에 대해
what has happened so far?
구체적으로 얘기해 줄래?
The expansion of the Kunad Gate,
쿠나도 게이트도 커지고
Togetsu Faith's real motive and their plans.
토게츠교의 진짜 얼굴과 그 의도라니
Kagero.
카게로
I never thought you'd be one of the immigrants from 2000 years ago.
네가 이천 년 전에 달에서 이민을 온 사람일 줄은 몰랐어
I look surprisingly young, am I not?
제가 의외로 많이 어려보이죠?
You people have gathered important information.
다들 엄청 많은 정보를 알아냈구나
Considering what you faced in the secure site,
아라하바키에서 일어난 일도 그렇고
you exceeded my expectation.
다들 생각보다 너무 잘했어
Thank you.
정말 고마워
But Naomi...
하지만 나오미가…
And Nagi too...
나기도…
We must stop Togetsu's insane ambition.
토게츠의 망상을 반드시 막아야 해요
But what is Karen planning to do?
그나저나 카렌은 대체 무슨 생각인 건지
What we know for certain is that
한가지 확실한 건
he activated the Red Strings and traveled through time.
레드 스트링스를 이용해 타임 점프를 했다는 거지
Fubuki, Alice was kept inside Seiran's Other research facility, right?
후부키, 앨리스가 세이란의 특이생명 연구 시설에 있었던 거지?
Yes. The facility was built so we could turn her back to human.
맞아, 그 시설은 애초에 앨리스를 인류로 회복시키기 위해 지어진 거야
I knew it. That Other was Alice.
그 괴이가 역시 앨리스였구나
What do you mean?
그게 무슨 말이야?
Could it be...
설마…
One of the Others that saved us
맞아, 나오미와 함께 우리를 구했던 괴이 말이야
was Alice.
앨리스가 그 안에 있었어
Aunt Alice? But how?
앨리스 고모가 어떻게…
I think Karen showed up there to save Alice.
카렌은 아마 앨리스를 구하기 위해 그 자리에 나타났을 거야…
Did I fail again?
내가 또… 실패한건가?
I'll rewrite it as many times as it takes.
몇번이고 다시 고쳐써도 상관없어
He traveled back in time to alter Alice's destiny.
그럼 앨리스의 운명을 바꾸려고 과거로 돌아간 거야?
But why was he after Yuito?
하지만 왜 유이토한테까지 온 거지?
He needed Yuito's power to trigger the Red Strings.
레드 스트링스를 사용하려면 유이토의 초뇌능력이 필요한 모양이야
"As many times as it takes," he said.
몇번이고 다시 고쳐써도 상관없다고 했지?
Does it mean it wasn't his first attempt?
과거로 몇번이나 다시 돌아갔었다는 거야?
Karen, to think you'd go this far...
카렌, 이렇게까지 해야만 해?
If my memory serves right, Aunt Alice was your fiancee, Major General Fubuki.
앨리스 고모는 후부키 연대장님의 약혼녀가 아니었어요?
Indeed.
맞아
Luka, will you tell the others?
루카, 내가 얘기해도 돼?
Yes. Since we'll be working together closely from now on,
네, 앞으로 우리 모두 함께 움직일 텐데
I don't want to keep any secrets from them.
숨기는 건 맞지 않다고 생각해요
For Karen and I,
앨리스와 카렌 그리고 나
Alice was our comrade in the OSF
이렇게 셋은 괴이 토벌군의 동료였고
and also our childhood friend.
어릴적부터 친구였어
The three of us had known each other for so long.
우리 셋은 아주 오래 전부터 함께 지냈었어
SCARLET NEXUS
"스칼렛넥서"
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
나른해 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
관계를 이룰 방법을 못 찾은 건가
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
귀찮은 친구가 있어
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
죽을 때까지 누군가의 포옹을 원해
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
겨우 숨 돌리는 혼돈과 허무함 속에
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
승리와 실패 사이에 목표를 둬
♫Not to be running out of patience for now I’m trying to be careful♫
믿음을 벼랑 끝으로 몰지 마 조심해
♫You'll see I'm always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 궤도에 말이야
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
흔들었던 날들에는 없는 재난
♫Where is the glory buried♫
영광은 어딘가에 묻어둔 지 오래
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
이 순간 외로운 야수가
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫To pierce with the theory♫
세상의 모든 이치를 꿰뚫어
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫It’s the same today To connect vividly♫
오늘도 여전히 함께해 똑똑히 연락해
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 정의에 말이야
KAREN'S AMBITION
(카렌의 염원)
"KAREN'S AMBITION" When we first met Karen,
카렌과 처음 만났을 때는
Alice and I were still little kids.
나도 앨리스도 모두 어렸어
Alice, are you really going?
앨리스, 진짜 갈 거야?
I don't think you need to rush it.
너무 조급해하는 거 아니야?
Maria from our class has already been scouted.
같은 반 마리아는 벌써 스카우트 되었다고
That's unacceptable.
안 내키는 걸 어떡해
Getting scouted early doesn't make one an outstanding OSF soldier.
일찍 스카우트된다고 대단한 토벌군이 된다는 법은 없잖아
But I want to be scouted as soon as possible.
그래도 빨리 스카우트돼서
I want to become a soldier of OSF to protect everyone.
모두를 지키는 토벌군이 되고 싶어
I'll get my check-up done and prove to them I have the power.
지금 당장 검사 받고 내 능력을 증명할 거야
Would the hospital examine you?
병원에서 검사해줄까?
That's why I need my dad to...
그러니까 아빠한테 부탁하려는 거잖아
Are you all right? Do you need a doctor?
괜찮아? 의사 불러줄까?
Leave me alone!
떨어져
I don't need anyone's help.
난 도움따위 필요하지 않아
What's wrong with him?
쟤 왜 저래?
I knew it. They won't examine you.
역시 안된다고 하시지?
What is it?
뭐야, 할 얘기가 남았어?
Luka, let's go.
가자, 루카
The next day, we came to the hospital again
다음 날 우리는 루카가 걱정되어
because we were worried about Luka.
다시 병원에 찾아갔어
The two brothers had been staying in the hospital.
동생과 함께 장기 입원한 환자였어
He seemed very rude.
겉으로는 싸가지 없어 보여도
But it wasn't long before we learned how kind and gentle he was.
실은 부드러운 사람이란 걸 알아내기까지 시간이 얼마 안 걸렸어
I am Alice Ichijo.
난 앨리스 이치조야
I am Fubuki Spring.
난 후부키 스프링이고
What is your name?
넌 이름이 뭐야?
Karen.
카렌…
Karen Travers.
카렌&nbsp;트래버스라고 해
Then, Alice and I started to visit him at the hospital every day.
그 뒤로 나와 앨리스는 매일같이 병문안을 갔었어
Soon enough, we became friends.
그리고 곧 서로의 그림자가 되었지
You too, Luka.
루카 너도 함께
But why was he at the hospital?
그런데 왜 입원한 거야?
Both of them were.
그것도 형제가 같이 입원이라니
That was because my brother and I
나와 형은
weren't born with any power.
태어날 때부터 뇌능력이 없었어
We were Bell Peppers.
벨 페퍼라고 하지
Bell Peppers?
벨 페퍼?
The test subject seems to have no recollection of ever being a Bell Pepper.
피험자는 벨 페퍼였던 때의 기억을 잃어버린듯 합니다
Fubuki, did you...
후부키, 혹시…
Yes, I know. Karen told me.
카렌한테 전해 들었어
I see.
그랬구나
My brother and I were test subjects of a power development experiment.
나와 형은 지속적으로 초뇌능력을 개발하는 실험을 받아야 했어
They treated us like animals.
마치 동물을 대하듯 우리를 괴롭혔지
The only hope we had
그때 우리한테 유일한 희망은
came from Alice and Fubuki.
앨리스와 후부키 뿐이었어
They told us about the world out there,
두 사람은 바깥 세상에 대해 얘기해줬어
their school, families, and friends.
학교와 가족 그리고 친구 얘기도 했었지
For the two little boys who were locked inside the hospital,
매일 똑같은 병원 생활만 해야 했던 우리한테
their stories were brilliant.
그 이야기들이 너무나도 눈부셔서
Once we've developed our powers,
초뇌능력을 사용할 수만 있게 된다면
we'd be part of that brilliant world too.
언젠가 우리도 그 눈부신 세계에 합류할 수 있을 것 같았어
That was the thought that kept us alive.
오로지 그 희망만으로 버텨왔어
Karen's strength gave Alice and me courage.
카렌의 굳은 의지 역시 나와 앨리스에게 용기를 주었지
No matter what happens, we must never give up.
어떤 상황에 부딪혀도 절대 고개 숙이지 않는 것
What's wrong with her?
얘 왜 이래?
Another classmate has been scouted by the OSF.
같은 반에 또 토벌군에 스카우트된 애가 있나봐
Is my power really so useless?
내 초뇌능력이… 그렇게 보잘것 없는 걸까?
Alice's power is matter creation.
앨리스의 초뇌능력은 물질 생성이야
What about yours?
그럼 후부키는?
This is amazing!
너무 대단해
I am just as determined
토벌군이 되어서
to join the OSF and help our people as anyone else in the class.
모두를 돕고 싶은 마음은 정말 자신있는데
You are too weak to realize that wish.
너같이 연약한 애가 어떻게 소원을 이룬다고 그래
I won't give up.
난 절대 포기하지 않아
No matter what it takes, I will make it out of this place!
어떻게든 이곳에서 벗어날 거야
That's right. I can't fall behind either.
맞아, 나도 힘낼거야
Don't overdo it.
적당히 힘내
Karen, keep up the good work so you can get discharged.
카렌 너도 힘내서 얼른 퇴원해
I'll be waiting.
기다릴 테니까
Who cares?
별 걱정을 다하네
I'll be waiting for you too.
나도 기다릴게
After that, we can always be together.
우리 나중에는 늘 함께하게 될 거야
What is a fiancee?
에비부부가 뭐야?
We are getting married when we grow up.
어른이 되면 결혼한다는 뜻이야
Is Alice marrying Fubuki?
앨리스와 후부키가 결혼해?
That's right.
그래
But it was our family's decision.
그냥 어른들이 제멋대로 결정한 거야
That sounds great.
좋겠다
Brother!
형
We detected some minor reactions. Continue the attack.
미세한 반응이 감지되었어, 계속해서 공격해
Yes.
알겠습니다
Karen.
카렌
We'll be waiting for you.
기다리고 있을게
We'll always be together.
우리 나중에는 늘 함께하게 될 거야
What was that?
어떻게 된 거야?
What is this?
이건…
Brother...
형…
He stole his opponent's power!
상대의 능력을 빼앗았어
After that, my brother was recruited by the OSF.
그 뒤로 형은 토벌군에 스카우트되었어
At the same time, I was scouted too.
그리고 나도 입대했고
I was in the same cohort as Karen.
카렌과 함께 토벌군의 일원이 되었어
Karen!
카렌
Soon after, Alice joined OSF too.
얼마 뒤 앨리스도 입대했어
Alice Ichijo.
오늘부로 토벌군에 입대한
Officially reporting in.
앨리스 이치조라고 합니다
Congratulation on making it to the force, Alice.
축하해, 앨리스
I finally caught up with you.
드디어 따라잡았네
I'm not going to let you two get all the spotlight.
앞으로 너희한테 뒤쳐지지 않게 쭉 노력할 거야
Don't overdo it, newcomer. You might get yourself into trouble.
아마추어는 너무 노력하면 안돼, 위험하거든
I heard that just not so long ago
내가 듣기로는 너 얼마 전에
someone had to write a report as punishment for disobeying his superior.
상급 명령을 위반한 벌로 시말서를 썼다던데
Fubuki.
후부키
That's worth remembering. It's your 50th report.
50번째 시말서는 기념할 가치가 있다고
I can't keep something so funny from her.
재미있는 일을 나 혼자 알고 있기에는 아까워서 말이지
Karen could be one of the next Septentrions,
카렌은 거의 셉텐트리온 확정인데
but he keeps disobeying orders.
상급과 어울리지 않으면 어떡해
I don't plan to follow any unreasonable orders.
합리적이지 않은 명령은 듣지 않아
You might as well just get a promotion and be a commander yourself.
카렌 네가 토벌군의 상급이 되는게 더 낫겠어
I don't want to look after the weaklings.
연약한 자를 돌보는 건 귀찮아
We should leave that to Fubuki instead.
그런건 후부키한테나 시켜
Come on, you care about your comrades.
동료들을 엄청 챙겨주면서 아닌 척은
Well, why don't both of you become commanders?
그럼 카렌과 후부키 두 사람이 함께하면 되겠네
That could work.
가능할지도 몰라
Karen can be the top commander while I work as his aide.
카렌이 앞장서고 내가 서브해주면 되잖아
We could restructure the current army into different regiments.
아예 현 제도를 연대 제도로 바꿀까?
Don't decide everything yourself.
제멋대로 결정하지 마
We fought the enemy forces together.
우리는 함께 싸웠고
Alice's fighting skills had improved as well.
앨리스의 능력도 많이 늘었어
Are you all right?
괜찮아?
Thank you for saving me.
저기, 구해줘서 고마워…
Don't let your guard down.
방심하지 마
Sorry.
미안
I wonder how many times you've saved me.
너한테 몇번이나 도움 받았네
You two, are you all right?
두 사람 괜찮아?
Fubuki.
후부키
I'm glad you are safe.
괜찮아보여서 다행이다
This fool got careless again.
바보 녀석이 또 사고친 것 말고는
It wasn't anything too serious.
아무 문제 없어
And you've become even stronger.
넌 또 더 강해졌겠네
But make sure you don't get too reckless.
그래도 조심해
Karen, you're hurt.
카렌, 너 다쳤어
Sorry, it was my fault.
미안, 괜히 나 때문에
I'll treat your wound now.
내가 도와줄게
Never mind. It's just a scratch.
됐어, 살짝 스쳤을 뿐이야
Fubuki, Alice is exhausted.
그나저나 후부키, 앨리스가 힘들해서
Keep her company.
네가 함께 있어줘라
I'll check the other areas.
난 다른 곳으로 가볼게
Karen!
카렌
Two years later...
2년 뒤
The Extinction Belt has reached the lower altitude of certain areas.
단절의 띠가 부분적 지역에 엄청 내려앉았어
It's a rare phenomenon.
아주 흔치 않은 현상이었지
Brain talk will be disabled.
브레인 토크가 안되니까
Don't let your guard down.
조심해
I'll take point.
내가 먼저 가볼게
Karen, don't rush too far ahead!
카렌, 너무 앞서 가지 마
I can handle it here.
여긴 나한테 맡기고
Alice, assist Karen.
앨리스 넌 카렌을 도와줘
Yes.
응
Karen!
카렌
Alice!
앨리스
What...
뭐야…
Alice, is that you?
앨리스, 너 앨리스야?
Alice, stop!
앨리스, 멈춰
The same happened to my sister.
언니처럼… 되었군요
Alice was sent to the OSF hospital afterward.
그 뒤로 앨리스는 토벌군 병원에 수용되었어
She was treated as a test subject.
그리고 실험 상대로 되어버렸지
Only the government and a handful of people know about this.
이 일은 정부와 일부 사람들만 알고 있어
You want to bust Alice out of the hospital?
앨리스를 토벌군 병원에서 구출시키겠다고?
Do you even know what the consequences will be?
그 후과가 어떤지 알고 이러는 거야?
You cannot stop me.
날 막아도 소용없어
If you refuse to help, I'll do it myself.
하기 싫다면 나 혼자서라도 해
Have you found a place to settle her down?
구출하고 어디로 데려갈지 생각해뒀어?
My family owns Spring Pharmaceuticals. They have a base in Seiran.
우리 스프링 제약이 세이란에 거점을 하나 두고 있기는 해
You could use that.
아마 도움이 될 거야
We got Seiran to assist us
우리는 세이란의 협조를 받아
and successfully rescued Alice from the hospital.
앨리스를 구출하는 데에 성공했어
But for a very long time after the rescue,
하지만 그 뒤로 오랜 시간 동안
the best we could do was imprisoning Alice.
앨리스를 유폐시킬 수밖에 없었어
We saved her,
구하긴 했지만
but also set her on a worse fate.
더 잔혹한 운명에 시달리게 했지
We were so lost.
많이 곤혹스러운 나날들이었어
I thought about giving up.
포기하자고 얘기해봤지만
But Karen refused to listen.
카렌은 전혀 흔들리지 않았어
He insisted on saving Alice.
여전히 앨리스를 구하려고 애썼어
Then, we can always be together.
우리 나중에는 늘 함께하게 될 거야
Karen traveled back in time
카렌은 과거로 돌아가
to change Alice's fate.
앨리스의 운명을 바꾸려고 했던 거네요
That seems to be the case.
아마도 그런 것 같아
Karen did travel through time.
카렌은 확실히 타임 점프했어
But Alice didn't come back to life.
하지만 앨리스는 여전히 부활하지 않았어
He went back in time, but nothing has changed in the present.
과거로 돌아갔지만 역사를 바꾸지 못했구나
Did he run into some setbacks?
진행이 순조롭지 못했던 걸까?
We wouldn't know.
모르지
But we can focus on what we can do.
우리는 최선을 다 할 수밖에 없어
I agree.
나도 같은 생각이야
Indeed.
그래
Karen's intention still worries me,
카렌이 마음에 걸리긴 하지만
but the more pressing matter is to stop Togetsu's plan.
지금은 토게츠의 계획을 막는 게 우선이야
But how?
하지만 어떻게 막을 거야?
We can stop Togetsu's mainframe, BABE, from functioning.
토게츠의 제어 컴퓨터인 베이브의 운행을 멈추면
How does that sound?
어떨 것 같아?
The researches on Red Strings
레드 스트링스의 연구 보고와
and their plans of operations are all in there.
실행 계획이 모두 베이브에 있어
Under these circumstances,
지금의 상황으로 볼 때
if you came up with the most viable plan,
너희 선택이 최선일 것 같아
I'll follow your lead.
나도 너희 생각에 따를게
If you're stopping Togetsu's plan,
토게츠의 일은 너희한테 맡기지
is there anything I can do to help?
내가 도울만한 건 없어?
Can you deal with Suoh and Seiran?
스오와 세이란이 화합하면 좋을 것 같은데
If the tension between them ease up,
양측의 관계가 안정적이면
Togetsu's operation will be undermined.
토게츠의 행동도 어느 정도는 막을 수 있을 것 같아
I'll try my best to make them call for a truce.
그럼 휴전 합의를 할 수 있도록 생각해봐야겠어
Both Suoh and Seiran have very little trust in Togetsu.
스오와 세이란은 모두 토게츠를 믿지 않아
That should be enough to persuade both sides.
이걸 이용하면 진행이 쉬울 거야
I'll try my best.
한번 해볼게
Don't overdo it.
너무 무리하지는 말고
I'll leave the rest to you, Sister.
누나야 말로 무리하지 마
That means we must infiltrate Togetsu's base.
토게츠에 잠입이라
How can we get in there?
작전 방식은 생각해뒀어?
Based on the information Kagero and Kyoka have,
카게로와 쿄카가 제공한 자료로
we could come up with a plan.
전략을 세워야지
We'll need your help, Kagero, Kyoka.
잘 부탁해, 카게로, 쿄카
Leave it to me.
응, 우리한테 맡겨
Kagero?
카게로
I think we can still use that cavern system.
저 동굴을 또 한번 이용할 수 있을 것 같아
It's the same passage we used to escape.
우리가 나올 때 통과했던 동굴인가?
Are we going to run into that Other again?
또 그 괴이와 싸워야 하는 거야?
What do you think, Kagero?
카게로 네 생각은 어때?
Sorry, but can we discuss the plan later?
미안한데 작전은 나중에 짜면 안될까?
Yuito, before we set out for Togetsu, I need to have a word with you.
유이토, 토게츠에 가기 전 너한테 할 얘기가 있어
A word with me?
나한테?
Let's not talk about it here.
여기서는 불편하니까
We should talk outside.
밖에 나가서 얘기하자고
Since everyone is present, you should listen to it too.
다들 모였으니 함께 듣는 것도 나쁘지 않겠어
What is this about?
하려는 얘기가 뭐야?
It's your father.
네 아버지인
It's about Chairman Sumeragi.
조 스메라기 평의회 의장님에 관한 얘기야
My father?
우리 아빠?
The man who killed him
그 자를 죽인 사람이…
was me.
바로 나야
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
추구하는 동경에 사로잡혀
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
아른거리며 앞을 막는 햇볕을 제껴
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
여태 본 적이 없어
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
공포는 묻어두고 하늘 높이 날 수 있을까
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
예쁘게 춤추는 새들과
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
빨갛게 물든 하늘을 쳐다봐
♫I chased after the gust♫
강한 바람을 따라가
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
변해가는 세계에 경치가 퍼지고 있어
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
뒤얽힌 빛 속에서
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
계속해 내일 걸어갈 길을 찾아
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
나아가
♫Have no fear for anything♫
더 이상 아무것도 두려워하지 마
♫Now, let's go♫
함께 가
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
KAGERO'S CONFESSION
(카게로의 고해)